很好
Ah,perfect!
Ben! Ben!
Ben，Ben
什么？
What?
听着Ben，我需要你帮忙，好吗？
Hey,Ben,look! I need your help,OK?
我想让你这样，首先你去……
Here's what I want you to do,first...
这样又会给我惹麻烦吗？
Is this gonna get me in trouble again?
Ben，我是你的大哥哥
Ben,I'm your elder brother.
从来没给你惹过麻烦。
No,I'd never get you into trouble.
孩子们。
Hi,guys!
妈妈。
Hi,mom.
Hey,mom!
谁把报纸扔得满沙发都是？
Who left the paper scattered all over the sofa?
是他。
He did.
什么？
What?
没关系，妈妈
Don't worry mum,
我来收拾，然后我再向Ben解释他错在哪。
I'll clean it up then I'll explain to little Ben where he went astray.
真遗憾，我还以为这是Seaver的家。
I'm sorry. I thought this was Seaver home.
我会给你颜色看的。
That's gonna cost you.
好的，听着
Yeah,all right,all right. Ben,look.
你帮我解了围。我来帮你代做功课。
If you help me out tonight,I'll do your homework for you.
你来代我做功课？
You'll do my homework?
Mike，我担当不起！
Mike,I can't afford it.
好吧，我给你现金。
Ok,all right,look. I'll pay ya.
一百。
A hundred bucks.
2块。
2 bucks
成交！想让我干什么？
Deal! What do you want me to do?
好的，到这
Ok,first. Come here.
你去把爸爸叫下来
Now I want you to get Dad down here,
让他坐在沙发上。
and have him sit on the sofa right here,Ok?
问他一个问题什么的。
And then ask him a question.
问什么？
About what?
随便什么都行，
It doesn't matter. Anything.
你就说想和他谈谈，
Just tell him you wanna talk to him.
这种话爸爸最听得进去，
Dad's pushing over when one of us wants to
咱们要和他打开交流的渠道。
open the channels of communication.
然后呢？
Then what?
我现在去把东西拿来。
I'll take it from there,thanks.
爸爸！爸爸！
Dad! Dad!
什么事？！
What?
请你坐下来，请向我解释，性的问题，好吗？
Will you uh,sit right here and explain sex to me?
这会？
Now?
我要在五点之前知道。
I've got to know by 5 o'clock.
你又在看医生讲座节目了？
You've been watching Dr. Ruth again.
好……
All right,Ben,look.
你们好啊。
Hey,guys!
晚饭的味道真香啊。
Ah,dinner smells great,Dad.
爸爸你一直看报纸有什么新闻吗？
I see you've been reading the paper. Anything interesting?
这个……
Well,I…
噢，真有意思，爸爸。
Ah! Very interest,Dad.
你知不知道受过驾驶教育的青年
Did you know that teenage drivers
开车的安全系数都很高？
with drivers' education have
呵呵。
Ahhhh…
这段话你信不信--
And Dad,would you believe what they says here?
少年开车者的汽车保险率，近年来降到了最低点。
Car insurance fares for teenage boys are at their lowest level in years.
你信不信Ben？
Would you believe that,Ben?
我承认这个人很会讲话。
You got to admit it. The guy is smooth.
爸爸你看这个，
Ahhhh! Dad,look at this.
这是我理想的汽车，1972年出的，只有2795美元。
My dream car,1972 V.W red top for a mere 2795.
但不是特别能讲。
Um,but not smooth enough. Come on,
这事你以前提出来过。
Mike. We've been through all this before.
可是我们并不打算帮你买汽车。
Now we're not gonna buy you a car.
你需要证明
You are going to have to prove that
你值得拥有一辆车
you are responsible enough to own a car
靠你自己赚钱
by earning the money for it.
既然说到工作
And since that means getting a job
估计你在我们有生之年也难赚辆车啦
it's conceivable you won't own a car in our lifetime!
好消息！我找到工作了。
Hey! Great news,Dad! I got a job. Yeah.
明天下午我开始去汉堡包房上班。
I start working tomorrow afternoon at the World of Burgers.
这是工作许可证明。
Here's a proud consent for my work permit.
请签个字。
Just sign here.
我早说了这个人挺有一套的。
Like I said,the man is smooth.
-= Subripped by Susie Shi =-       2007.07.23
他们连大声嚷嚷都不会。
Why can't I have parents who yell?
这次又闯什么祸了？
What you do this time?
呵，
Ha!
我老实告诉你吧，
For your information,
他们现在正在讨论
they just having a meeting deciding
是否让我去汉堡包房打工的问题。
whether let me take a job at World of Burgers.
有谁什么雇你？
Somebody hired you?
好吧，好吧你笑吧，
Oh,fine,fine. Go ahead and laugh.
我刚才听见了，
But I just happen to know that
爸爸妈妈对我去工作很有信心。
Mom and Dad have great deal of faith in me.
可是我根本没有信心。
I have no faith what so ever that
他能打工上课两不误？
he can handle both job and school.
意见一致了。
So we agree.
可话也说回来，也不能让他泄气啊。
At the same time,we can't just give up on him.
你是想说
You're going to say that
他一生中第一次
for the first time in his life
想靠工作赚钱，
he wants to work for something,
为什么咱们不给他机会呢？
so why don't we give him the chance.
对，并且。。。
Yes,and…
并且你认为找工作能成为他的一个转折点？
And you think that getting this job could be a turning point for him.
对，并且。。。
Yes,and then…
我知道，你还认为要孩子好就得冒点险。
I know. And you think when you love your kids it involves some risks.
一点不错。我还有别的想法吗？
Exactly! Do I think anything else?
我讲得也差不多了。
No,that about covers it.
是吗？你会讲什么我也知道。
Well,I think I know what you gonna say,too.
你认为他有了工作
You are gonna say that with this job
就会把学习彻底放掉
he's gonna forget about his school completely.
他会变成一个拥有汽车的退学生
And then we've got a drop-out with a car
整天闲着。
and a lot of time on his hands.
对。
All right.
他第一次开车出去
And then the first time he takes that car out
就会遇到一个二十三岁的女人
he's gonna meet a 23-year-old woman.
他就再也不去上班了
And then he's gonna quit his job
因为他再没时间卖汉堡了。
because he has no time for burgers any more,
你懂我的意思吗？
you know what I mean?
于是他疯狂的想着开车
Coz all what he wants to do is drive,
并且就象发疯一样地开着车
and he wants to drive so fast coz
去约会。
he's going to Lovers Lane.
去约会时开车太快
Yet he's gonna to Lovers Lane so fast that
车子失去了控制，突然撞上了另一辆汽车，轰
the car spins out of control and hits another car-bomb!
又成了另一个故事。
And there's a bull,but that's another story.
就算没有人受伤，
And even though nobody's hurt,thank Godness,
Mike也够倒霉的了。
Ah,Mike's still in trouble. Woo…
因为他的驾驶执照就要彻底地作废了，
He let us car insurance expire.
完了。接下来，看门口
No! And next,look out at the door.
该轮到那个二十三岁的女人了
there she is a 23-year-old woman.
对，就是她，这时候她的肚子里已经有孩子了。
Yes,that one. And here she is,heavy with child.
她宣布说非嫁给Mike不可，
Yes,and she wants to marry Mike now.
我们一下子又多了一个带着小孩的小孩
Now we got a kid with a kid,
工作没了，收入没了，保险没了，甚至前途都丢了。
and no job,no income,no insurance and no future.
全给你猜着了。
You read my mind.
Maggie，你是否认为你的反应过分了？
Huh,you think you're over-reacting just a little?
我？
Huh,me?
好吧。咱们俩看到了问题的两个方面。
Ok,we both see both sides of the question.
关键是怎么做。
So what do we do?
应该做一对理智
Well we do with any sensative,
关心，爱护的父母该做的事。
loving caring parents would do.
我来押人头。
And I call heads.
爸爸，
Ah,Dad!
也不知道是
Ah,you know,I,ah,
哪个冒失鬼把杯子放在地板上了。
just picking up this glass,someone throws it on the floor,
多半是Ben。
probably Ben.
我们在讨论是否让你打工。
Well,we were just discussing your job.
打工？打什么工？
Job? What job?
哦，汉堡包房。
O,World of Burgers.
我都快忘记了。
It just slipped my mind,you know,
我读书太专心了。
I've been studying so hard.
好了，Mike，
Umm. Well,Mike.
我们经过了仔细的研究
We've been giving careful consideration
而且考虑了问题的所有方面。
of both sides of this question.
最后我们对你做出了
And after carefully considering it,
一个慎重的决定--
we think that we will be taking a great chance.
冒险帮你签。
But,we're gonna sign those papers…
好极了，我一定不会让你们后悔，我保证。
Yeah! All right! Dad,you guys will not regret this!
可如果你的学习成绩……
You just make sure your grades don't…
你别开玩笑了，
You know,Mom,Dad.
我可以保持平均的及格水平。
I will promise I will make a solid D average.
可是我们的要求要高一点。
I think we were hoping for something more.
我豁出去了，那就及格加。--好！
Oh,wait. Whatever you want? D-plus grade. YEAH~!
Jason，这硬币两边都是人头。
Jason,this nickel has two heads.
不是更好吗？
What's your point?
听着，这是饮料中心，
Now,e,this is the beverage center.
这是大号的，特大号的，极大号的。
Ok. Large. Extra large. Colossal.
噢，天哪。
Ah~! Woo!
不不，这是极大号，这才是天哪号。
No,no. This is colossal,and this is Woo.
噢，对。
Oh!
对不起，克拉斯特先生。
Excuse me,Mr. Krassener
不，Terry，我不是说了吗？
Now,Terry. I told you before.
我喜欢职工们叫我的名字
I like my employees call me by my first name.
好的，史古特。
Ok. Scooter.
我……我觉得那个叫什么来的被吸住了。
I think those watch-you-ma-callit things are clogged.
是说润滑油嘴？
Not the Greace traps?
是的。
That's it.
天啊，得赶快修。
Oh my God! Excuse me.
Hi. Hi.
HI，
HI，你也是新来的。
Are you new here,too?
是的，第一天。
Yes,its my first day.
我是第二天。
It's my second.
我不知道
I don't know.
这么复杂。
It's all so complex.
别逗了。
Are you kidding?
克拉斯特先生，哦，史古特他要说是我干得好的话
Mr. Krassner,Scooter,Says if I really apply myself,
就能当本月的明星职工。
I could get to be employee of the month.
就象乔依斯·卡特一样。
Just like Joey Scavuglio.
你真敢梦想！
Duh,its a dream.
奶酪汉堡包，多点土豆条，
Titanic Cheese Burger,considerable fries
啤酒要"哗"号杯，一个基本套餐
and a Woo beer,a diet quota.
和我说吗？
You talkin to me?
对，大哥哥。
Oh,brother.
好，请你稍等一会好吗？
Ok. No sweat,I can handle this,Ok.
这是极大号，我要"哗"号的。
That's a colossal. I said,a Woo.
噢，说得对，稍等。
O! Right. Sorry.
唉哟。土豆条。唉哟。
All right with you. Ou! Ha,ha,ha,ha…
你忘了汉堡包了。
You forgot my Titanic Burger.
噢，对，请你稍等一会。
Right. You're right. Be right with you in just a ...
业余水平。
Amateurs.
好了，一份疯狂的房子不要胡桃，
Ok. That's one Mad House no nuts
一只大汉堡包不加生菜，
one Titanic Burger,hold the ice burg lettuce,with one considerable fries
两杯冰茶，一杯"呼啊"，一杯极大不放冰，
two ice teas,one Woo,one colossal no ice
一份冰淇淋，核爆炸式的。
one patti melt-down with nuclear dressing.
周围散落的是薯条。
Fries on the side
我知道，我没看错。
I knew it was right,...Look at him go.
核爆冰淇淋？
Patti melt-down
我赌五美元，他会找错钱的。
I'll bet five dollars he messes up to change.
我也愿意和你睹。
I'll take that action.
9和10块，谢谢。希望你们下次再来
Nine and ten. Thank you and as we say at WOB,
光顾本店。呵呵，
don't get any onion. O!
你们全家都来光临了？
What a charming little family here.
欢迎来汉堡包房，请问要点什么？
Welcome to the World of Burgers! How may I help you?
我们只是看看。
Well,we just came to look.
来了不吃怎么行？
Well,you got to order something,Dad.
好吧，就来烤羊肉串。
Ok. I'll take a meal on a stick...
不，不行。不准吃垃圾食品。
No,you don't. No junk food.
妈妈。
Mom…
家里已经烧好晚饭了，
We had a nice dinner already at home.
我不希望他脂肪吃得太多。
I don't want him loading up on grease.
不管吃不吃都会让他丢饭碗的。
Double or nothing,he's out of here in 10 minutes.
Mike，你可是咱们家出的第一位明星职工。
Mike,we've just never have an employee of the month in our family.
我们只是想来看看你是怎么工作的。
We just came down to see you work.
我一向很喜欢穿制服的人。
I've always been a sucker for a man in uniform.
真的吗？
Yeah,you have?
我们有样东西想要你惊喜一下。
Mike,we have a little surprise for you.
噢，小惊喜。
Oh,a little surprise.
反正你一下班，就直接回家。
Anyway. Be sure you come straight home after work. OK?
好的。
Ok.
HI，我是经理，有什么问题？
Hi! I'm the manager. Is there a problem here?
不，这什么问题也没有。今天我在这吃早饭，
No,none whatsoever. I was down here for breakfast this morning,
这位小伙子的服务态度太好了，
and this young man gave me such incredible service.
所以我想把全家带来和他见见面，
I just wanted to bring the whole family down to meet him in person.
好了，孩子们，咱们走吧。
So kids,we'd better be going.
但是，你们要记住这一天。永远。
But,I want you to remember this day,always.
Mike，我不知道该怎么办，
Mike,I don't know what to do.
这人想要多要番茄酱。
This guy wants extra ketchup.
我想劝他别了。
I tried to talk him out of it.
听着Terry，你用不着紧张。
Terry,Terry,would you just relax.
没法不紧张，我要是搞糟了活儿就没了。
I can't relax. Mike,if I mess up again I'm out of here?
你放心。不会丢的。
You're not gonna mess up,Ok?
Terry，你收钱的抽屉还开着！
Terry! Your register draw is open!
是这样的，史古特，都是我的错
Ah,look,Scooter. That's my fault.
刚她休息完，她不在，
Since you just came back from a break
两个抽屉都是由我在管。
and I was handling both registers while she was gone.
Mike？我不能相信你是本月的明星职工。
Mike? I,I,I don't believe it! You're the employee of the month!
对不起，
Yeah,look,I'm sorry. Scooter,look,
我要吸取教训，
I have learned my lesson,
你听我的心跳，每分钟能跑一英里。
my heart is just beating a mile a minute here.
Mike，你真肯帮助人。
Huh,Mike. That was so nice of you.
如果你要我为你效劳的话，
If there is ever anything I could ever do for you,
你就直说好了。
don't hesitate to ask,Ok?
呃呃，这个嘛。
Well…
Mike!
Mike
史古特？
Oh,yes,Scooter!
现金账上怎么少了三十七美元？
This cash register is 37 dollars short!
我，我不知道该说什么。
I,I,I,I just don't know what to say.
请你相信我，这事绝对不会再发生。
Look,Scooter,I'm sorry. It will not happen again.
知道了。
I know.
什么意思？
What does that mean?
对不起，我也没有办法，你被解雇了。
I'm sorry. My hands are tied. You,you're fired.
解雇了！妈妈，爸爸？
Ah,fired! Mom,Dad?
爸爸出什么事了？
Dad something's happened today?
惊喜！
Surprise!
这点小礼物是送给明星职工的。
A little something for our employee of the month.
我真为你自豪。
Mike,we're so proud of you!
Mike坐在驾驶盘后面，
Mike's still sitting there behind the wheel
一直张着嘴巴。
with his mouth hanging wide open.
他还在流口水。
Has he start drooling yet?
Carol，你还是少开点玩笑吧
Carol,if you'd stop making fun for one second,
应该学学你哥哥的榜样。
you might learn from your brother's example.
要我把Mike做榜样？
I might learn from Mike?
对，他的学业有进步，打工的表现也很好。
Yes,his grades are up,he's doing very well at the job.
他没有把钱浪费在买录音带上
And instead of wasting his money on Scritty Polity records
而几乎全都攒了下来。
he saved almost all of it.
我每门功课都是优，家务全是我做的，
I have straight A's,I do all my chores around here
我宁愿死也不去买波尼迪的录音带。
and I'd sooner kill than spend a nickel on Scritty Polity
你从来就是个好孩子。
But you have always been a good kid.
这也是我的过错吗？
That's my crime?
Carol，我们是说像你这样一个模范孩子
Oh,Carol. What we're saying is that even a model child like you
也能从Mike的进步中得到教育。
can learn something from Mike's accomplishment.
你们的意思是说哪怕我调皮捣蛋一辈子，
So if I'd spent my whole life as a total screw up,
但只要干一件好事，
and then did just one thing right,
也能赏我一辆汽车？
I'd be given a car too.
招聘国际化妆品公司销售代表，
Wanted sales representative for international cosmetic firm.
诚聘有朝气有抱负青年。
Looking for young aggressive self-starter.
每月薪金六千美元，
Interested in 6,000 a month minimum,
擅长土耳其语！都有门槛！
is fluent in Turkish. Always a catch!
带我去迪斯尼世界，快踩油门。
Take me to Disney World,step on it!
我倒要踩你了！
I'm gonna step on you!
你这样可不像个有责任的新Mike。
You don't look like a new responsible Mike.
新这样讲？
Who said that?
爸爸在回家的路上讲的，当时妈妈都哭了。
Dad did on the way home from World of Burgers,and mom was crying.
哭了？
Crying?
就象Carol进尖子班那样。
Well,like she did when Carol joined Mensa.
还是爸爸妈妈认为我没出息的日子好过得多。
You know,life was a lot better when mom and dad thought I was garbage.
那我还认为你没出息。
I think you're garbage,Mike.
谢谢你。
Thanks.
能呆会吗？
Can I stay?
干嘛不行？
Why not?
想知道这辆车的价格吗？
You wanna know how much the car cost?
不。
No.
一共花了2605美元！
2,605 dollars!
Ben!
还要加税款，执照费和佣金……
Plus tax,license and dealer prep.
要是你再说一句他们为我自豪的话，
Look,if you say one more word of how proud they are of me,
你就给我离开这！
you gonna have to leave.
好吧！
Ok.
可我并没有要他们信任我，对不对？
I,I didn't ask them to have faith in me,did I,right?
有还是没有？
Yes or no?
没有。
Um,no.
说得很好。
That's right.
那好。
Good.
他们也应该估计到我会把事情搞糟的。
They should know I'm gonna find a way to mess things up,right?
到底怎么回事?
What's the problem?
你搞糟了？
You messed up?
没有。
No!
噢。
Oh.
可我并不想进去让他们伤心。
I mean. I'm not about to go in there and break their little hearts.
我不能干那样的事，对不对？
I can't do something like that. Can I,Ben?
当然
Sure.
是不能。
No!
对，我就这意思。
Ah,that's what I meant.
所以我得干我非干不可的事。
So,now I have to do what I have to do.
可以。
Right.
Ben，要是你想免除痛苦，
Look,Ben. If you want to save yourself a lot of grief,
千万别让爸爸妈妈对你抱太多指望，
don't let mom and dad expect great things from you.
让他们知道你是不可救药的。
Let them know your a real disappointment now.
Maggie!
Jason!
你在啊
Oh,you're here.
Maggie!
Jason!
我以为你去开门了。
Thought you were gonna answer.
我以为你去开了。
I thought you were.
知道你们在家，我听见声音了。
I know you are in there. I can hear you.
你好。
Hello?
HI，我是Terry，Mike在家吗？
Hi! I'm Terry,is Mike home?
不在。
No.
他的制服在家吗？
Is his burger uniform home?
没有，他穿着呢。
No,he's wearing it.
噢，那太让人伤心了。
Oh,that is so sad.
Terry，我是治精神病的。
Terry,I'm a psychiatrist.
不，我现在是汉堡包房的经理助理，
Well,I,I'm the new assistant manager at World of Burgers,
我需要那件制服。
and I need his uniform.
Mike也需要。
Oh,well,Mike needs it.
为什么？
For what?
为上班！
For work.
真是好极了！
That's great!
他被解雇我都快伤心死了。
I felt so bad when he got fired. Well,
等一下。
Hold it!
什么等一下？
Hold what?
Mike被解雇了？
Mike was fired?
你不知道？
You didn't know?
天啊，我又闯祸了！
O,boy! I did it again.
好象是Mike又闯祸了！
Seems like Mike did it again.
我撒谎了。他没有被解雇。
I lied. Ah,he didn't get fired.
听着，我根本就不认识他，
Look,I,I don't even know him.
我是个精神失常的人，就喜欢收集制服。
I'm just an insane girl who collects Burger uniforms.
呃……就算我没来过这，好吗？
Ah,just forget I ever came by here,Ok?
根本没那事。好吧，再见。
This never happened. So,bye,bye!
HI，爸爸？一对一怎么样？
Hey,dad! How about some one on one?
现在我正忙着呢，Ben。
No. I'm too busy right now,Ben.
忙着干什么？
Doing what?
我在忙着把我的愤怒情绪升华，
I'm sublimating my angers so I get my negative emotions under control
把消极情绪转化为比较积极的情绪，懂了吗？
and have a more constructive attitude,Ok?
噢，祝你成功！
Oh! Good luck!
HI，妈妈。
Hi,Mom
Hi.
他正忙着呢。
He's busy.
你说对了。
You were right.
对什么？
I was?
咱们不应该让Mike去打工。
We never should have let Mike take that job.
OH，Jason，我倒希望我说错了。
Oh,Jason. I didn't want to be right about that.
你瞧这，来吧，看见了什么？
Look at this. Look. What do you see here?
是一滩油迹。
A grease spot.
这不仅是一滩油迹。
It's not just a grease spot.
他象征着我上了当，
This is a symbol of my gullibility.
一个值两千六百美元的当。大当。
A 26 hundred dollars symbol of my gullibility.
加税款，执照费和佣金总数就是这些。
Plus tax,license and dealer prep,whatever the hell that is.
亲爱的，我不认为你上了当，因为……
Oh,honey. I wouldn't call you gulable,I'd say you were...
愚蠢，对吗？
Stupid?
我是说你很信任人。
Well,I was going to say trusting.
对Mike信任等于愚蠢。
Well,with Mike,trust is stupid.
亲爱的，信任Carol是容易的，
Oh,honey. Trusting Carol is easy,
Ben也不成问题，因为
and Ben's no problem because,well,
他是家里最小的一个。可是信任Mike就需要……
he's smaller than us. But trusting Mike is a real…
请不要说愚蠢两个字了。
Ah,very good. You're back to stupidity again.
我再也不信任Mike了，Maggie！
I'm not trusting him any more,Maggie.
Jason，他辜负了我们的信任，可是……
Jason,I know he let us down,but maybe there is some…
他骗了我们整整一个星期，只是为了保住他的那辆车。
Oh,you know,he lied to us for a solid week just so he wouldn't lose that car.
我倒真想看看，Mike几时能考虑一下别人。
And I really sick of Mike thinking of nobody but himself first.
你这么大的火最好现在别去跟他谈。
you know,Jason. Maybe you shouldn't talk to him when you're this angry.
一点也不错。
Absolutely.
可你会。
But you will.
一点也不错。
Absolutely.
HI，爸爸。
Hey Dad!
这不会是我那工作努力的儿子和他得之无愧的汽车吧？
Well,if it isn't my hard working son and his well deserved car?
是的，都是的。
Yeah,that's us,Dad.
我都快要累坏了。爸爸。
You know I'm really bushed today,Dad.
汉堡包房今天怎么了？
So how you go down at the World of Burgers?
看上去像是弄了点洋葱
Looks like you got some onion.
我老实对你说吧。
Yeah,well,to tell you the truth,Dad.
对我说？什么？
Excuse me,the what?
说老实话，嗯，
Tell you the truth. Ah,
我在汉堡包房受了点挫折。
I don't know,I'm getting a little bummed with WOB
你不是这个月的明星职工吗？
Oh,but you're the employee of the month.
可也给我带来了很大的压力。
Yeah,you know,there's a lot of pressure there,dad,
他们想让我去给经理当助理，
and I don't know. They are talking about making me an assistant manager.
那样我得先去上汉堡包大学了。
That would mean i'd have to go to burger college
可我吃不准是不是上大学的料的。
and I just don't know if I'm university material.
这么说，你已经打算辞掉这份的工作啰。
So you're telling me that you're considering quitting this job?
我在排队等一个更好的差事。
Well,I've already got a better job to lined up,Dad.
这是一个汽车工业的活。
Yes,in the auto-motive industry.
福特，通用，还是克莱斯勒？
Ah! Ford? General motors? Crysler?
波尼
Burney.
波尼？
Burney?
对，波尼洗车公司，我要当一名洗车工，
Yeah,Burney's car wash. I want to be a rag man,Dad.
酬金丰厚，前途灿烂。
Tips galore and a great future.
完了，说不下去了，
Oh,I can't do this.
对你我就不能当面说谎，因为你有特异功能。
I can't look you in the face and lie. What is it,some kind of magic power?
Mike，我……
Mike,I have…
爸爸，我被解雇了。
Dad,I got fired.
甚至都不是我的错
Ok,it wasn't even my fault. Dad,I mean,
我为了掩护一个叫Terry的姑娘,她把收银机一直开着
I was covering for this girl named Terry who left her register draw open.
我本来想告诉你的。可那天你正好送我汽车。
Sorry,I wanted to tell you but I guess that was the day you gave me this car.
你叫我怎么对你开口呢。
What was I supposed to say then?
对，你不希望失去你的车。
Oh,yes. You didn't want to risk losing the car.
爸爸，我不是为了那辆车。
Oh,dad. It wasn't because of the car.
我是说是的，但不是你说的意思……
I mean,it was,but not the way you mean.
那天，我是破天荒第一次
It was just such a new experience,I mean,
让你为我感到自豪，
how could you be so proud of me?
我都搞糊涂了。
It confused me.
我也被搞糊涂了。
Well,it confused me,too.
你还不明白吗？
So don't you see,dad? I mean,
我是不愿意让你认为我是个不可信赖
I just didn't want you to think I was some loser
甚至是不可救药的人。
who couldn't be trust with any responsibility.
正当你开始信任我时。
Just when you started having faith in me.
你对我也应该有点信心。
Well,you've got to have a little faith in me,too.
算了吧，爸爸。
Oh,come on,dad,no.
要是你发现我已经被人解雇了，你会在这团团转，
If you had somehow found out that I was fired,
对妈妈说信任我有多么愚蠢。
you'd be out here pacing,telling mom how stupid you were to trust me.
你这样说也许也可能。
Well,possibly we may…
爸爸，你要知道
Dad,don't you see,you know
向你隐瞒真相我有多么的难受。
how hard it's been for me to keep the truth from you?
你隐瞒是为了我？
So you lied to me for me?
对，我不能辜负你对我的信任，
Yeah,I just didn't wanna let you down.
不管发生什么事都不能。
No matter what happened to me it didn't matter.
这点我很赞赏。
Well,I appreciate that.
Mike，我们一定在等你。
Michael? We've been waiting for you.
Maggie，Mike对我说他的那份工作一星期前就丢了。
And Maggie,Mike just told me he lost his job at the Burger place last week.
他说了？
Oh he did.
我真是大吃一惊！
I was shocked.
怎么会？Jason，他瞒了我们整整一个星期！
You were? Jason,he's been lying to us for an entire week!
是的。真是个了不起的孩子。
Yes. Is that a great kid or what?
反正由于错误的理由干下的错事和
So there's a difference between doing the wrong thing for the wrong reason,
由于正确的理由干的错事是有区别的。
and the wrong thing for the right reason.
有问题吗？
Any questions?
没有。
No,no,no.
很好。
Ok.
等一下，我有个问题。
but,wait,I have a question.
上个月我打碎了妈妈珍贵的瓷器，
Last month I broke some of mom's good china,
可我为什么没有得到奖赏呢？
how come I didn't get a reward for it?
可你要知道世界上有错误的事，也有正确的事。
See there're wrong things and there're right things.
错误的不正确的事总是不应该得到原谅的。
Now the wrong things sometimes do...